Resident Evil is a franchise that has lost its mind more times than all other franchises combined.
I was hoping the 7th one would be the silliest game of all time.
But Capcom failed...
I like the Franchise, the first 3 games ruined sleep for every 90's kid.
Then came a game that was really good, so it sold a lot.
Then came a game that was kind of bad... So it sold a lot.
This caused Capcom to have a mental breakdown and create a game that was so bad, it's amazing.
Resi 7 begins with a video message from a woman telling us she is tired of her babysitting job...
What kind of mororn becomes a babysitter in a horror franchise?!
Then she records another message telling us to stay away.
Which is horror language for "Come here right now".
It cut's to our hero Ethan driving he has received a message from his dead wife Mia.
Telling him to come to "Silent Hill".
No...
Louisiana
Much scarier.
Often Horror games begins with warning signs, but here it is welcoming stuff like. "Join us" & "Accept her gift".
I think we're going to have a good time.
With a cozy sect.
There's also this... Uhhhh, but never judge a cult by the way they treat their cow legs.
We enter this dirty house, never understood that about horror antagonists.
What's with their hatred of vacuum cleaners?
In the house we find a VHS tape.
In a game that takes place in 2017...
Then it makes sense it's so dirty no one has been here since 2001.
A VHS player.
It's a recording for the t.v series "Sewer Gators".
So i'm not going to watch it because all reality t.v is fake.
Thanks to "Lets Plays" I know where I'm supposed to go.
Get yourself a nice bath.
With a friend.
See a lit room...And here we -- find Mia.
Well all right then.
We did it.
That was easy.
And that's the Kilian experience.
"Filler Nightmare Music"
She screams we have to leave because daddy is coming.
I get it.
She was never dead she was just so embarrassed about Ethan that she faked her own death.
So her parents wouldn't have to meet him, I didn't think Resident Evil would reflect my life...
The duo decides to leave, but the door has disappeared.
Too bad, i'm going to look for snacks.
Huh, a doll...That is in no way foreshadowing.
Now the door is here, but now Mia has disappeared.
Maybe they switched places.
There she is!
What...The...Fuck Mia...
You need to floss.
She throws Ethan and then tries to stab him.
She has threw me 4 meters why does she need a knife??
You stink Mia!
Have some Axe!!
Dead.
A phone is ringing somewhere.
Hello im Zoe.
And what you just saw was a "Splicer".
You need to get out of there right now.
Uh, unless you are a Door to Door Salesman.
Then stay....Everything is fine.
Okay then I shall walk out.
Miaaa!
About that scar...
Okay you are angry.
Okay you have a Chainsaw!
Haha joke's on you I'm, not even left handed.
Upstairs we find a gun.
Okay here we go again.
She should really learn how to duck.
Dead.
Again.
Ethan gets knocked out.
We see him being dragged and then his arm re-attached with a staple gun.
We are at a fancy dinner party!!
This is the Baker family.
But there is no bread.
That's when you know something is wrong.
Could also be the human we are eating.
But that might just be English food.
Then they leave me without someone to watch over me.
I know a trap when I see one so I'm staying!
Fuck it time to explore.
Never mind!
In the hall there is a key to a hatch.
We can hear the Dad walking above us.
The Japanese sure know how to make some scary stuff.
There's this
Silent Hill 2.
That one Beyblade episode.
That had the haunted train.
We enter the first safe room.
Resident Evil is a "Survival Horror" game.
Survival is a code word for "Few item slots".
But you can put stuff in a chest.
That uploads your items to the cloud.
How does that work???
They use VHS tapes and the clock can measure your health.
Technology is all over the place.
Zoe calls again and says we need to get out of the house.
Thank you Zoe.
But no i'm planning to stay here.
Maybe settle down.
Out of the save room someone is knocking somewhere.
All right a police officer.
Now would be a great time not to be vague and explain exactly what is going on.
So the officer is like...
Sir are you locked in there with a bunch of murdering psychopaths?
And Ethan is like.
I don't know am I?
If you give me a weapon maybe I'll tell you.
They decide to meet up in the garage.
Hiya friend.
uhhhhhhooooo
Are you okay?
Ahhh grab a painkiller you'll be fine.
Boss fight, the best way to beat him is to grab the car because cars kill everything.
Oh noes he's taken control of the one thing that can kill everything.
And he used it to kill himself...
Oh no he is alive, save me car!
And then he shoots himself.
Was I ever in any real danger?
After that we find a horse body.
No not a real one sadly.
Use the body as a key and now the game opens up.
For the remaining time we are going to go around solving puzzles and finding keys.
Yeah the game suddenly turns into.
Resident Evil.
I-I-I-I know it's on the cover and everything.
But I still consider it a plot twist.
Our first mission is to collect 3 dog heads.
No not real ones.
Sadly.
First one clock.
Second one book on the second floor.
Here we also find a reason everyone is so dirty.
Oh it's our old friend.
What gives him his healing powers?
He says "My little girl has given us a gift".
I don't want to spoil the ending just yet.
But...it's yoga.
But he is like really good at it.
To get the 3rd dog head we need to traverse a basement.
Full of Mushroom People.
And get the Scorpion key.
Instead of helping me the officer has decided to take a nap.
Annnnd Boss fight.
Chainsaw duel.
Give up sir knight you've got no upper body.
Now we can go outside.
Ahh Louisiana...Lots of history.
One time the French showed up to a place.
With swamps and Alligators.
and said this seems like a great place.
It wasn't a great place.
In the backyard there is a trailer that has free underwear.
Zoe calls us again.
Ethan me and my family are sick
and the only thing that can cure us
is KFC.
Mother has buckets...and refuses to share.
Would you kindly go get them for me.
Cross the bridge and enter this house.
Full of giant bugs.
Or just bugs if you are Australian.
I need bug spray.
But the house only has gasoline spray.
The place is being patrolled by mother Baker.
She can control Mosquito's many say this game was inspired by PT.
But so far we have Stealth.
A person that can control bugs.
And an old person who is the worlds greatest sniper.
That last one might not be confirmed yet, but if the Soviet's show up Konami is going to sue.
Find a crank raise a bridge get the Crow key.
Now we can enter Old lady.
Mini Boss.
She has a lantern I have a flamethrower.
And she melts.
Like in Super Mario Sunshine.
Was she a Plant?
No we can finally get our K...F
ffff the fuck?
Here's a recipe for a cure.
Zoe will get the head and I shall get the arm on the top floor.
To get there I need to balance her lantern on this scale.
Why not just hold it down.
Also most doors are made of wood.
But I can't burn them.
Beginning to feel like this game about magical viruses might not be realistic.
Mother boss fight.
Yeah she's gone full insect.
Therefore she wont come near me because I used a Mosquito roll on
before I entered.
That makes me immortal!
She bit me!
At this point Ethan had been through a lot of disgusting stuff and not showered once.
The taste was not what she expected.
One bite and you die.
I am actually offended right now.
Time to go to the creepiest part of them game.
A child's room!
Ooh a Teddy bear.
And it's leaking.
No way this passed factory regulations.
Ewww disgusting.
Then there is a girl.
She is a child in a horror game so i'm guessing she has Psychic abilities.
Return to trailer, receive a phone call.
Heyy Ethan...it's Lucas Baker.
I kidnapped the girls and had all this crazy stuff planned.
But I just found out about club penguin.
Just uh...
Just come here and get the Snake key.
So we get the key from the body of the sleeping policeman.
Why is there a Scorpion key, a Snake key and a Crow key?
Why the specific species of this of them and why crow.
Hippopotamuses kill 500 people a year, why not a Hippo key?
Get 2 key cards and head to Lucas' place.
This whole segment is not scary just annoying.
He lures us into a monster arena we gladiator now.
Which reminds me Russel Crowe traveled from Austria to Spain so fast that his bleeding hadn't stopped yet.
Compared to that, this was easy.
Blah blah blah bunch of stuff happens.
We did it!
Mia and....Zoe.
She looks way too normal.
Then Father Baker is back he's now a monster.
We defeat him by shooting him in the eye.
Why's it always the eyes in video games?
Never any deadly areas.
Time to save him by injecting the vaccine.
And he hardens and dies.
huh the anti-vaccors were right.
But now we only have one vaccine left.
Do we save Mia orrrrrrr.
Do I know you?
Now Mia and Ethan are leaving on a boat.
And there is a bigger boat.
And "SPOILER ALERT" here comes the big reveal.
The gas tanker did it.
A ship is a she and she would have gotten away with it too, if she wasn't a 200 meter inanimate object.
The game says my theory is wrong.
Now we get to explore the ship as Mia.
Ethan has been kidnapped by a black worm thingy.
Time to save him.
The ship...looks a lot...like my room...
We keep seeing the little girl.
There's like a 40% chance she's responsible for this.
The girl tells us to play a tape that will...BLOW MY MIND!!!
It's Frozen of course it is.
Wha
She is like 10 years old.
Why'd I expect something else.
Hey look Ethan is trapped in a cocoon.
Maybe if we wait here he will turn into a beautiful butterfly.
Yayy Mia saved us.
And tells us to leave because she is adopting the little girl or something.
I-I don't care i'm tired of her shit.
Oh look Soldiers are showing up.
I've played enough horror games to know they will shoot me on sight
For some reason we end up in a salt mine.
And it's a boring action part.
The mine has a room completely filled with exposition.
You know the stuff I don't allow on my YouTube channel.
There is also a "Kill the final boss serum".
Then we return to the first house.
The Grandma was the little kid all along.
It was pretty obvious if you've been paying attention.
We see flashbacks that shows us that she was behind the attack's at the beginning...Allegedly.
Maybe she is just taking the blame.
Maybe all of this was just a trick to restore Ethan and Mia's relationship.
Let's go beat up an old lady.
Vaccine style.....And she melted.
Maybe I injected her with water and she was a witch.
Or maybe not.
Uhh final boss.
Grandma has turned into a Dark Souls and we have to fight her the only way I know how.
Beybladeeeeeeeeeee
Beybladeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeee
Calcium!
Finally soldiers show up and one of them takes off his helmet and reveals himself to be.
Norman Reedus
The screen turns white and Silent Hills the game was a playable teaser for the next Silent HIll.
WHAT A TWIST!
Cancelled!
And that is the Kilian Experience.
Hello everyone if you are interested there is a Kilian Experience DIscord now, link in the comments and the description.